hey everyone thanks for listening to the
grow your life podcast my name is jeremy
krakowski if you haven't listened this
podcast yet i help coaches trainers
authors and mentors grow get more
clients make more money and live the
life of their dreams to thrive and not
just strive and struggle and if that's
you if you're somebody that wants to
grow and reach your goals as a coach as
a trainer and make a whole heck of a lot
of money doing it you're in the right
place now today i have the privilege to
talk with somebody that i absolutely
love
don palacios she is a registered
dietitian
a coach a trainer and a mentor that
helps people thrive in their life
and and helps entrepreneurs specifically
thrive with their energy their focus and
just be able to do a whole lot more of
what they're called to do so dawn
welcome to the show i think you're going
to really help a lot of people today how
are you doing today i'm fantastic and
i'm honored to be here thank you so much
hi
everybody so
tell me a little bit about you what you
do
um tell the listeners that and and how
you got started doing that sure well i
believe it's my personal mission and
passion to really teach people to take
back control of their health so that
they can massively increase their energy
thrive and live a life they love and you
know as a my background is actually a
clinical oncology dietitian and i worked
in the hospital system
which i loved early on in my career for
10 years but i realized a few things i
was working all the time i lived with a
pager i was always on call and i wasn't
enjoying life uh and then the other
thing is that i saw so many people
that i wasn't able to help them i was
getting to them too late especially in
the oncology field and i realized after
a decade that i had to make a shift that
i needed to do more preventive work and
help people before they got the
diagnosis of cancer and so that really
put me on a mission to figure out what
can i do
and uh it was really after i moved to
austin that i decided i'm gonna start my
own business and i'm gonna figure out
how to do this that's awesome and you
and you at that time you had some of
your own health challenges too didn't
you i did actually yeah at that time um
i went from you know being a very
healthy you know uh late 30-year young
woman to just having trouble sleeping i
was having digestive issues i started
getting a lot of pain and in the midst
of it i lost my little brother and so
the grief and the trauma of that just
really you know um compounded everything
and that made me do what a lot of people
do right you go to the doctor to find
out what's wrong and all of my blood
work showed up normal and you know i
spent two years chasing things and
nobody could give me an answer right and
it was really really frustrating and i
just had enough of it i'll never forget
the day that i said i'm done i'm gonna
figure this out on my own wow yeah i
think what's amazing about you is you
are
somebody who practices what she preaches
and what you do for people you have also
done in your own life
you've made money in your business
you have changed your mindset you have
changed your eating you have changed
your health and so what you help people
do you have increased your energy what
you help people do comes not just from
book knowledge but also experience i've
tested it test not guess but you have
you've proven it and you've proven it
with clients that you've worked with
like
guys i just want to tell you this if
you're somebody that needs more energy
and you struggle with that you think
maybe it's related to your health
connect with dawn after listening to
this honestly she's one of the best
people that can help you with this we'll
we'll put a link to her website here on
the screen as well what's your website
url yeah it's
pauldawn.com awesome
sounds amazing so so tell me a little
bit about about some of the work that
you do and how you help people yeah
absolutely well it's interesting that
you say about my story because i was
embarrassed when all that was happening
to me i was really afraid to share that
i was embarrassed because i couldn't
figure it out
and now that i've done so much healing
um you know with my my soul my mind and
my body and i finally uh became
vulnerable to share my story it's the
number one reason people want to work
with me is because not only do i have
all the certifications all the alphabet
letters behind my name and the degrees
but i've lived it out i know where
they've been and i can relate to them
and you know that just gives me a unique
perspective to be able to to come in and
to serve support and and guide them
right and i think what makes me
different is that i realize again coming
from that clinical background is that we
have a very sick care model of
healthcare in this country where you
know when we have aches and pains and
different symptoms um you know medicine
conventional medicine and i don't blame
anybody because i was trained this way
too you manage the symptom with surgery
or with medications but it doesn't
really help people up level their health
so that they can be maximally productive
and live that life they love because
we're not going after the root cause in
modern medicine and that's what made the
difference for me and that's what i do
and that's what makes the number one
difference for all of my clients so give
me a little bit
i guess elevator pitch slightly of like
how you get them there what you offer to
people yeah absolutely well you know
it's something that i learned from you
obviously is learning you know what are
those challenges that they're facing
right you know and all of the women that
i coach you know these are women just
like me they are starting to go through
that perimenopause menopause transition
um they are exhausted all the time but
yet they can't sleep um you know uh they
are trying to reach a healthy weight um
but the weights increasing um even
though they're eating healthy things and
they've got bloating and digestive
issues and you know and so by leading
with that and connecting with them you
know that's the number one thing and i
start off by offering people to just
jump on and do a live master class with
me and really help them to understand
why they're feeling the way that they do
and why everything they've tried doesn't
work and starting to give them some of
that information that's incredible and
that's so valuable right there and and
it just goes to show so you have this
live master class that you do and then
you walk people through this process and
they go through
your your funnel and your offer and then
they get to work with you more closely
um but let's go back to what you talked
about
you felt
embarrassed about your story
you know
vulnerability i'm not sure this is a
brene brown quote but it's based off of
some of brene brown's information i
think vulnerability your income earning
potential is directly related to how
vulnerable you could become
and i see a lot of people protect
themselves from appearing like they're
not perfect they don't have it all
together
i i had spoken with a with a lady a
couple months ago how she was like i
just i i can't even imagine not doing
everything in a way that appears perfect
online and and and and a lot of that
comes from fear trauma
just what people told us things like
that what was one of the things that got
you
past that what were some of the mindset
things that got you to to that place
where you felt like a not just
comfortable sharing but realizing
it's actually profitable in my business
and to not share would be a detriment to
the people that i'm helping yes well
after i started working with you one of
the things that we started really
working on was to to develop the mindset
of an entrepreneur right and so number
one i needed to do some therapy to heal
myself right you know
myself like many of the women that i
have the privilege of coaching we are
the first generation women to work
outside of the home and build a thriving
career and you know with that is a lot
of excitement but also a lot of that we
have a lot of things that were modeled
to us that we've taken on that have
caused these limiting beliefs and i
didn't realize that at the time until i
started going through the therapy and
then number two
having an insatiable appetite for
reading and learning and i over the last
several years have just devoured every
kind of book i could on helping to
change my mindset and you know uh we
have something called neuroplasticity
where we can literally retrain our brain
and once i started to tap into that it
became very empowering and i realized i
don't have to live like this i can take
back my power and i can re-train my
brain to overcome these limiting beliefs
and it was just just
absolute breakthrough for me yeah you
use some of that with your clients oh
100 it's the number one thing that we
work on we work on mindset before we
ever work on nutrition in fact i'm
working with a client right now one on
one and we've spent the last six weeks
just helping to heal her mindset you
know she she shared with me that you
know all of her health issues and weight
struggles went back to when she was five
years old five years old and you know
she's been carrying this around for 40
years so i knew after she shared that
with me that if i just gave her a diet a
healthy diet
uh it wasn't gonna work we had to work
on the mindset and giving her the space
to heal and shift that and learn to love
herself learn to love herself and then
develop new
positive affirmations again retraining
her brain and it's been absolutely
transformational i want to i want to ask
you this just real quick for some of the
listeners here you know i've i've spoken
with a number of the different listeners
they
avoid social media because they think
that they need to lose 50 pounds or 100
pounds to get on social media
um and and that's a very real thing a
like we know that you don't have to but
like
i don't want to invalidate the what
they're feeling as well as well i'm i'm
not going through what they are for
women it's a whole different than men i
i've struggled with weight my my life as
well but for women some of that like if
you were coaching a a client who was
like
insecure with how they look
and they they lack energy and they they
want to lose weight but they struggle
with that and it goes back to their
childhood like what would be one of the
things that you would say to them to
encourage them to get breakthrough if
they're listening to this podcast yeah
yeah the number one thing i ask women is
do you believe that you're worth it to
take back your health and so many of
them with that one simple question that
is the pivotal question because they
don't even believe that they have worth
right uh and and in this society
especially in people
they do they told them they're worthless
unless they look for certain ways yeah
we have these diet culture lies you know
we are bombarded not just with social
media but magazine ads movies television
commercials you know it starts with
little girls playing with barbie dolls
and you know hair and makeup and it's
just we take these things on as our own
and think that that's the norm that we
have to fit into that and if we don't
fit into that we're worthless and so it
has to start right there and i just
simply tell them i'm giving you
permission you are worth it you are
loved by your father god and you are
absolutely worth it and it starts there
it starts there and for those of you
listening i'm i'm actually like
getting emotional hearing dawn say this
because i know for those of you
listening that might have been the first
time that you've ever heard somebody say
what don just said
yeah yeah absolutely you might have had
a dad that told you that you were
worthless and a boyfriend that told you
that unless you lost 20 pounds he'd
break up with you yes
i i hear these stories from from women
up all the time on my social media yes
and then you don't want to be a bad a
bad girl or a bad wife or a bad
person by not doing what other people
want and and we
buy into these stories that we have to
live for what other people want yes
exactly exactly and that's that's not
how we're designed to be that was never
god's intention for us right god's
planted unique gifts inside of each one
of us and but i wasn't able to tap into
those true gifts until i gave myself
permission to to love myself and do the
work of healing and that is you know the
number number one thing for for
everybody whether it's health or you
know uh building your own business right
um i could not grow in my business and
you remember when we first started
working together i'm like i'm doing all
this stuff but why isn't why aren't the
sales coming in because my head and my
heart were not in alignment with the
vision that i had right we have to do
that work and that's why i decided that
that had to be the number one thing i
couldn't like worry about the copy or
the perfect ad until i got myself
together right yeah that's so good yeah
that is so good what was one of the
biggest like aha moments that you had
when you realized
wait a sec
because a lot of people
listening and
think well if only i just had the next
strategy if only i just had the next
way to write copy then my business would
grow if only i just had the cutting edge
and here's the thing i'm telling you
i've known dawn for
a couple quite a few years now
you had all the latest cutting edge
strategies yet for whatever reason it
wasn't working for you yeah it wasn't
the biggest it wasn't working all myself
right and like i said i really attribute
a lot of this to um believe it or not
lots of books but i uh during the
pandemic you couldn't go to the gym you
couldn't go anywhere so i started
walking every morning and i would listen
to audio books and i i went through on
hyperspeed the jen sincero you're a
badass series
and i mean for somebody like to tell me
you are a badass right there you go you
know and and and you know um that was
just transformational right to to
actually
think that i could make unlimited
amounts of money that i could do
anything in the world because that was
never spoken to me you know i grew up
with the mindset of money doesn't grow
on trees and so i took that on as my own
and it was at that moment when i heard
jen say that you are limitless and you
can do anything that i realize i've
gotta i've gotta rewire my brain and and
you know not blaming for what i brought
on but you know
taking back my power by changing my
trajectory right wow yeah absolutely
that is so powerful listen that book
uh you are a badass by jen sincero and
you are a badass at making money and
she's got a whole series of books he
does i recommend them to people if
you're listening to this podcast go
check out those books as well
dawn this is incredible hearing this
what is
one thing that you would say to coaches
and trainers right now
if they
they they have an idea for a business
right they know what they want to do
most people who listen they know what
they need to do
but they're struggling with
actually doing the work actually showing
up
yeah or
they're doing the work and it's not
producing results and they're getting
burnt out by that yeah what would you
say two things two things take imperfect
action right number one thing i've
learned from you and many of my mentors
you know it's never gonna be perfect
you're gonna change it 999 000 times uh
and that's okay it's an experiment but
you've got to get started right if you
have an idea just get started right um
get on that call with jeremy jeremiah
and start coaching um but get started
that's the number one thing and then
number two if things aren't working i
wouldn't i would actually encourage you
to look at your energy what is your
mindset and what is your energy and
that's the other thing that i really
have had to work on and i work on every
day with self-discipline is
whatever energy we have our words and
our thoughts are energy so whatever we
think whatever we speak we're projecting
an energy out to the universe right and
as entrepreneurs trying to build a
business a coach any type of a
mentorship if we have any kind of
negative thoughts we speak negative
words we're projecting that out there
and that's why the sales are not
happening that's why we are not
magnetically attracting our ideal
clients so the number one thing that i
do every single day
as i come into my office is i spend an
hour i call it my power hour and i work
on raising my vibrational energy i have
a whole routine around this the phone by
the way is not allowed in this space um
but you know i actually will do my
prayers my meditation my reading
i put on music and praise and worship
anything i can do to get my head on
right and raise my energy before i work
and then i work out and eat right that
is all so important before i sit down at
my desk here to start working with my
clients working on an offer whatever it
is that's the number one thing that was
missing because you were teaching me
great strategies i was learning all
kinds of things but i kept saying to you
on our coaching calls what what's
happening what's not working and i
finally realized that it was me again
it was my mindset and you know
raising our energy being grateful living
with an attitude of gratitude is a game
changer absolute game changer now now
let me ask you this just on that
um
especially coming from your background i
think that a lot of people who listen to
this can relate
what if things in your life are going
crappy like are you just in denial
no that doesn't mean that i don't have
pity parties they happen right you know
i allow myself to have a little fit and
cry
but you know i'll set a timer almost and
do that right because i know
i know now i've trained myself if i stay
in that pit too long it's going to
affect everything so if i don't deny it
i allow myself to feel it and experience
it kick a pillow scream do whatever i
need to do cry right and then i just get
back into it right i reset i release it
that's the big thing releasing it and
letting it go and and i will physically
like say i release this i let it go
right i am not going to carry this
around right and that is so powerful and
so healing and then i'll just put on
some good old music and dance it out and
and get back on it yeah i think we've
been trained for so long that we need to
bottle that up oh and we need to hold it
in right now what does that produce in
somebody's health life energy and and
what does that do yeah it creates a lot
of negative energy in the body and
actually any kind of toxins that we do
breathe in or that we eat are gonna get
trapped in your cells in your dna i am
working with clients in their 40s 50s
and 60s and we've traced toxins still
stuck in their bodies that we can link
back to high school days college days
you know um it's incredible right
because they bottled things up and it
just it layers and it's stifling to your
body and the body eventually is going to
break down i mean your body's always
trying to talk to you so all those
symptoms when you're exhausted and you
can't sleep and you've got migraines and
you've got digestive issues it's your
body's way of saying hey i need help
it's like the check engine light on your
dashboard going on oh that's so good
that's it but so many times we ignore
those check engine lights we want to
just put a band-aid over it and pretend
that it's not there we'll pop some pills
right
and
that's what we've been trained to do
because that's what conventional
medicine teaches us and we don't do the
work and we don't let it go and it just
stifles us and it shows up on the test
that i run on people it's mind-blowing
it's mind-blowing and it's really sad
that you know we have this sick care
model these are not expensive tests um
this isn't rocket science we have the
science and the technology to figure
this out you know um my goal always is i
want to help people get a real
transformation so that six months from
now they are thriving in life and they
don't need me anymore i don't want to be
the revolving door that they keep coming
back right
right
yeah
i got something i was going to share
with you you know on that uh just an
example of that like the body being a
check engine light so this past week if
i look at the last seven days
i was consistent with going to bed at
the same time eating the same eating
right however three of those days i had
almost no energy
and then two days after i had a really
hard conversation with somebody
and got some clarity on something i had
more energy than i could imagine yes yes
literally my energy was attached to the
worry and fear of that potential
conversation absolutely that's it we've
got to tune into that jeremiah people
have to tune into that and that's so
important for our health but in business
as well we have to tune into that and
allow ourselves to process and and work
through it and release it and not stifle
it absolutely so good
and and i ended up talking to my
therapist like after all that happened
and we found a breakthrough in that area
of
i've been avoiding conflict with people
for the last however many years
literally avoiding situations that could
potentially be conflict and so anytime i
go into one that could be my energy goes
like this right now here's a great story
to that
i had a potentially conflicting
conversation with a friend of mine an
hour before this podcast
my energy didn't dip once because i was
walking in that power and i was already
at a heightened state just like you
talked about
right there so i'm telling you what don
is talking about here is the truth it
works
you guys you you absolutely need to
connect with don you absolutely need to
if you're struggling with
building your business you're an
entrepreneur you're a coach or a trainer
and you want to know okay
i know what i need to do but i'm
struggling to be disciplined and i'm
feeling like i just had this mental fog
that's stopping me from doing that right
talk to dawn because honestly
i would bet that it has to do with
some of the areas that she helps with
what would be if somebody's dealing with
like mental fog that they just can't
focus i know for me a lot of it was i
was eating sugar and i think that that
addiction was causing a lot of that yeah
absolutely absolutely it definitely goes
back to what are we eating and the thing
is you know as as busy entrepreneurs
busy professionals you know you're
running on mach 5 all the time and
burning the candles at both ends right
and oftentimes that means that your
health is going to take a back seat and
so most of the people that i work with
you know they are eating takeout all of
the time and they're running to sugar
and or caffeine to keep themselves going
right and when i worked in the hospital
even as a dietitian i was doing that
because i was working 12 hours a day
right and so we have to get at the root
cause of all of that that's a lot of
toxins in the body so number one we
gotta find out what those toxins are
test don't guess right uh that's number
one and then number two it really is
around establishing a whole new routine
right you know like you said getting a
good bedtime routine not working till 12
o'clock you know in the morning right
good bedtime routine giving yourself
permission to stop and eat lunch and
chew your food right giving yourself
permission to just unwind off of social
media off a tv relax have fun you know
these are simple things but they are
absolutely game-changing and
transformational for your house and for
your business
a lot of entrepreneurs they say well i i
don't have time to chew my food or i
don't have time to
for self-care i don't have time to do
that because i'm so busy all the time
right well i look at all of those things
they're just excuses right they are
there are excuses bottom line it may
sound harsh but it's an excuse right i
say that to myself all the time and then
the other question is well how is it
working for you
how is that working for you how is
running on caffeine and takeout and not
sleeping well how is that working for
you because if you don't deal with it
now you're going to deal with it in 10
or 20 years when you get that diagnosis
from your doctor of heart disease or
cancer or dementia or something else
that that is the bottom line and people
don't want to believe that but we now
know through science and research that
that's exactly what causes 90 of our
chronic diseases in our bodies wow it's
purely lifestyle choices so we either
deal with it now
and get on and thrive in life or we deal
with it later and we just survive
through life amazing this has been a
powerful episode i i'm excited to hear
the feedback from people who got the
chance to listen to it um listen if this
has helped you and you're listening to
this episode be sure to plug in with
dawn head on over to her website at
pauldawn.com
and and
jump onto one of her master classes
schedule a call with her
talk with her don thank you so much for
being here with me this has been such a
blessing you're amazing i'm so proud of
you just
seeing how far you've gone oh well thank
you i am just honored and blessed and so
grateful to have met you and friends if
you are listening and you have not
started coaching with jeremiah you need
to jump on a call and start coaching
with him because it is the number one
thing that has helped me in the last two
years to go from zero to multiple six
figures and truly be able to live the
life of my dream so schedule that call
with jeremiah now
thank you i'd love to talk with you if
you're somebody that is a coach is a
trainer wants to get more clients and
grow your business you can go over to my
website schedule that discovery call and
we can work together we can look at your
business and dive into okay what's going
to help you get those results what's
going to help you get those clients as
well if this podcast episode has helped
you be sure to share it with somebody
don't just be
selfish with the information share it
with somebody else because you may never
know what you sharing an episode with
somebody will do in their life
all right thank you dawn so much for
being here thank you for those listening
grow your life everybody and we'll talk
soon have a good one